Guide to the Duke University Progress Pictures Collection, 1925-1932 UA.01.15.0012
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- East Campus, 1925-1926
  - East Campus Progress Picture #123, 1926 June 15 (Box 1, Print EC123)
    Center of site looking northeast showing Alspaugh and Pegram Residence Halls.
  - East Campus Progress Picture #124, 1926 June 15 (Box 1, Print EC124)
    East side of site looking north showing work on Union Building and Brown Residence Hall in background.
  - East Campus Progress Picture #125, 1926 June 15 (Box 1, Print EC125)
  - East Campus Progress Picture #126, 1926 June 15 (Box 1, Print EC126)
    Foundations of Baldwin Auditorium, looking northeast.
  - East Campus Progress Picture #127, 1926 June 15 (Box 1, Print EC127)
    Masonry work on Carr Building.
  - East Campus Progress Picture #128, 1926 June 15 (Box 1, Print EC128)
    Masonry work on Bassett Residence Hall, foundation of Baldwin Auditorium.
  - East Campus Progress Picture #129, 1926 June 15 (Box 1, Print EC129)
    Scaffolding and masonry work on [Lilly] Library, center of site looking southwest.
  - East Campus Progress Picture #130, 1926 June 15 (Box 1, Print EC130)
    Center of site looking northeast showing railcars, as well as masonry work on Union and Bassett and Brown Residence Halls.
  - East Campus Progress Picture #131, 1926 June 15 (Box 1, Print EC131)
    Center of site looking north showing scaffolding and masonry on [Lilly] Library and Alspaugh Residence Hall.
  - East Campus Progress Picture #132, 1926 June 15 (Box 1, Print EC132)
    North end of site looking west from roof of Bassett Residence Hall, showing Pegram Residence Hall and foundation of [Baldwin] Auditorium.
  - East Campus Progress Picture #133, 1926 July 1 (Box 1, Print EC133)
    Center of site looking northwest showing [Lilly] Library and Alspaugh and Pegram Residence Halls.
  - East Campus Progress Picture #134, 1926 July 1 (Box 1, Print EC134)
    Center of site looking southwest showing scaffolding and masonry on [Lilly] Library.
  - East Campus Progress Picture #135, 1926 July 1 (Box 1, Print EC135)
    Bassett Residence Hall and foundation of [Baldwin] Auditorium, north center of site looking east.
  - East Campus Progress Picture #136, 1926 July 1 (Box 1, Print EC136)
    Foundation of [Baldwin] Auditorium, looking northeast.
  - East Campus Progress Picture #138, 1926 July 1 (Box 1, Print EC138)
    Center of site looking northeast showing work on East Campus Union and Brown and Bassett Residence Halls.
  - East Campus Progress Picture #139, 1926 July 1 (Box 1, Print EC139)
    Center of site looking southeast showing foundation of Science Building [now Friedl Building].
  - East Campus Progress Picture #140, 1926 July 1 (Box 1, Print EC140)
    Center of site looking north showing [Lilly] Library and Alspaugh Residence Hall.
  - East Campus Progress Picture #141, 1926 July 1 (Box 1, Print EC141)
    North end of site looking east showing Bassett and Brown Residence Halls and foundation of [Baldwin] Auditorium.
  - East Campus Progress Picture #142, 1926 July 1 (Box 1, Print EC142)
    Identified as possibly the north end of Pegram Residence Hall.
  - East Campus Progress Picture #143, 1926 July 15 (Box 1, Print EC143)
  - East Campus Progress Picture #144, 1926 July 15 (Box 1, Print EC144)
    Center of site looking west showing [Lilly] Library scaffolding.
  - East Campus Progress Picture #145, 1926 July 15 (Box 1, Print EC145)
    Pegram Residence Hall and foundation of [Baldwin] Auditorium, north center of site looking west.
  - East Campus Progress Picture #146, 1926 July 15 (Box 1, Print EC146)
  - East Campus Progress Picture #148, 1926 July 15 (Box 1, Print EC148)
  - East Campus Progress Picture #149, 1926 July 15 (Box 1, Print EC149)
    Center of site looking southeast showing scaffolding of Science Building [now Friedl Building]. East Residence Hall is visible in background.
  - East Campus Progress Picture #150, 1926 July 15 (Box 1, Print EC150)
    North end of Carr Building.
  - East Campus Progress Picture #151, 1926 July 15 (Box 1, Print EC151)
    Center of site looking northwest showing [Lilly] Library and Alspaugh Residence Hall.
  - East Campus Progress Picture #152, 1926 July 15 (Box 1, Print EC152)
    Front of Union looking north showing end of Brown Residence Hall.
  - East Campus Progress Picture #153, 1926 August 1 (Box 1, Print EC153)
    East side of site looking northwest showing corner of Library (1902-1927); new [Lilly] Library; and Alspaugh and Pegram Residence Halls.
  - East Campus Progress Picture #154, 1926 August 1 (Box 1, Print EC154)
  - East Campus Progress Picture #155, 1926 August 1 (Box 1, Print EC155)
    Center of site looking northeast showing workers at site of old Alspaugh dormitory, Union Building in background. Not an original print.
  - East Campus Progress Picture #156, 1926 August 1 (Box 1, Print EC156)
    Center of site looking northeast showing Brown Residence Hall, railcar, and building supplies.
  - East Campus Progress Picture #157, 1926 August 1 (Box 1, Print EC157)
    North side of Carr Building. Worker walking along railroad track.
  - East Campus Progress Picture #159, 1926 August 1 (Box 1, Print EC159)
    Foundations of Science Building [now Friedl Building]. East Residence Hall is visible in background.
  - East Campus Progress Picture #162, 1926 August 1 (Box 1, Print EC162)
    Foundations and framing of [Baldwin] Auditorium.
  - East Campus Progress Picture #163, 1926 August 16 (Box 1, Print EC163)
  - East Campus Progress Picture #164, 1926 August 16 (Box 1, Print EC164)
  - East Campus Progress Picture #165, 1926 August 16 (Box 1, Print EC165)
    Excavation for Faculty Apartments [now Wilson Residence Hall].
  - East Campus Progress Picture #166, 1926 August 16 (Box 1, Print EC166)
  - East Campus Progress Picture #169, 1926 August 16 (Box 1, Print EC169)
  - East Campus Progress Picture #170, 1926 August 16 (Box 1, Print EC170)
    Center of site looking northwest showing Bassett and Brown Residence Halls.
  - East Campus Progress Picture #171, 1926 August 16 (Box 1, Print EC171)
    Excavation for Faculty Apartments [now Wilson Residence Hall], Union Building, and Brown Residence Hall.
  - East Campus Progress Picture #172, 1926 August 16 (Box 1, Print EC172)
    North side of Carr Building.
  - East Campus Progress Picture #173, 1926 September 1 (Box 1, Print EC173)
  - East Campus Progress Picture #174, 1926 September 1 (Box 1, Print EC174)
    Foundation of Baldwin Auditorium, looking northeast.
  - East Campus Progress Picture #175, 1926 September 1 (Box 1, Print EC175)
    Union Building showing scaffolding. Brown and Bassett Residence Halls in background
  - East Campus Progress Picture #176, 1926 September 1 (Box 1, Print EC176)
    Baldwin Auditorium steelwork, looking southeast. Bassett and Brown Residence Halls in background.
  - East Campus Progress Picture #177, 1926 September 1 (Box 1, Print EC177)
    Baldwin Auditorium steelwork, looking southwest. Pegram and Alspaugh Residence Halls in background.
  - East Campus Progress Picture #178, 1926 September 1 (Box 1, Print EC178)
    [Lilly] Library looking southeast
  - East Campus Progress Picture #179, 1926 September 1 (Box 1, Print EC179)
    Front of Union Building looking north showing end of Brown Residence Hall.
  - East Campus Progress Picture #180, 1926 September 1 (Box 1, Print EC180)
    Foundations for Faculty Apartments [now Wilson Residence Hall] and Science Building [now Friedl Building]. East Residence Hall in background and Craven Memorial Hall at right.
  - East Campus Progress Picture #181, 1926 September 1 (Box 1, Print EC181)
    [Lilly] Library and Alspaugh and Pegram Residence Halls from center of site looking northwest.
  - East Campus Progress Picture #182, 1926 September 1 (Box 1, Print EC182)
    Front of [Lilly] Library showing scaffolding and columns and south end of Alspaugh Residence Hall.
  - East Campus Progress Picture #187, 1926 September 15 (Box 1, Print EC187)
    Foundation and steelwork on Baldwin Auditorium, looking northeast. Bassett Residence Hall is at right.
  - East Campus Progress Picture #188, 1926 September 15 (Box 1, Print EC188)
    Foundation and steelwork on Baldwin Auditorium, looking southeast. Bassett Residence Hall is at right.
  - East Campus Progress Picture #189, 1926 September 15 (Box 1, Print EC189)
  - East Campus Progress Picture #190, 1926 September 15 (Box 1, Print EC190)
    Alspaugh and Pegram Residence Halls from floor of [Baldwin] Auditorium. [Lilly] Library roof is visible in background.
  - East Campus Progress Picture #191, 1926 September 15 (Box 1, Print EC191)
    View south from top of Union Building, showing foundations for Faculty Apartments [now Wilson Residence Hall] and Science Building [now Friedl Building].
  - East Campus Progress Picture #192, 1926 September 15 (Box 1, Print EC192)
    East Union Building, with Bassett Residence Hall and steelwork for Baldwin Auditorium in background.
- West Campus, 1927-1932
  - West Campus Progress Picture #1, 1927 April 12 (Box 2, Print WC1)
    From back of photo: "View Taken from center of quadrangle looking along quadrangle with location of Medical School in back ground."
  - West Campus Progress Picture #2, 1927 April 12 (Box 2, Print WC2)
    From back of photo: "View taken from center of quadrangle looking along quadrangle showing proposed location of dormitories in center of picture."
  - West Campus Progress Picture #3, 1927 April 12 (Box 2, Print WC3)
    From back of photo: "View taken from center of quadrangle looking across same with proposed location of Chapel at the upper center of picture. This shows fill being made between Union Building and Library.
  - West Campus Progress Picture #4, 1927 April 12 (Box 2, Print WC4)
    From back of photo: "View taken from proposed location of Chapel looking towards fountain showing the grading near center of quadrangle."
  - West Campus Progress Picture #5, 1927 April 12 (Box 2, Print WC5)
    From back of photo: "View taken from center of Quadrangle looking towards proposed location of fountain. This shows clearing for the building of large fill for main entrance to University."
  - West Campus Progress Picture #6, 1927 June 9 (Box 2, Print WC6)
    View looking toward Chapel site.
  - West Campus Progress Picture #7, 1927 June 9 (Box 2, Print WC7)
    View looking towards site of Medical School. Note curve in railroad track.
  - West Campus Progress Picture #8, 1927 June 9 (Box 2, Print WC8)
    View looking to dormitory site.
  - West Campus Progress Picture #9, 1927 June 9 (Box 2, Print WC9)
    Perhaps land to the east of the construction plateau?
  - West Campus Progress Picture #10, 1927 June 9 (Box 2, Print WC10)
    View from chapel site toward traffic circle.
  - West Campus Progress Picture #11, 1927 June 9 (Box 2, Print WC11)
    View of clearing work.
  - West Campus Progress Picture #12, 1927 July 8 (Box 2, Print WC12)
    Site of Library?
  - West Campus Progress Picture #13, 1927 July 8 (Box 2, Print WC13)
    Site of Academic Quadrangle showing railroad track. Medical School site is at center?
  - West Campus Progress Picture #14, 1927 July 8 (Box 2, Print WC14)
    Site of future causeway looking east, site of future gardens ot the left?
  - West Campus Progress Picture #15, 1927 July 8 (Box 2, Print WC15)
    Site of residential quads looking south along railroad track? Several workers' faces are visible.
  - West Campus Progress Picture #16, 1927 July 8 (Box 2, Print WC16)
    Valley north of future causeway looking east? Site of future gardens at left, steamshovel visible.
  - West Campus Progress Picture #17, 1927 July 8 (Box 2, Print WC17)
    Excavations in residential quad?
  - West Campus Progress Picture #18, 1927 August 4 (Box 2, Print WC18)
    Excavations for utilities in residential quad?
  - West Campus Progress Picture #19, 1927 August 4 (Box 2, Print WC19)
    Excavations for utilities on Main Quadrangle? Workers' faces visible. "The Duke Endowment, No. 1" visible on steamshovel.
  - West Campus Progress Picture #20, 1927 August 4 (Box 2, Print WC20)
    Excavations in Residential Quadrangle?
  - West Campus Progress Picture #21, 1927 August 4 (Box 2, Print WC21)
    View along future causeway looking west towards Main Quadrangle?
  - West Campus Progress Picture #22, 1927 August 4 (Box 2, Print WC22)
  - West Campus Progress Picture #23, 1927 August 4 (Box 2, Print WC23)
    Excavations for utilities, Main Quadrangle?
  - West Campus Progress Picture #24, 1927 August 8 (Box 2, Print WC24)
    Quarry?
  - West Campus Progress Picture #25, 1927 August 8 (Box 2, Print WC25)
  - West Campus Progress Picture #26, 1927 September 8 (Box 2, Print WC26)
    Excavation for hospital and medical school buildings, viewed from the north?
  - West Campus Progress Picture #27, 1927 September 8 (Box 2, Print WC27)
  - West Campus Progress Picture #28, 1927 September 8 (Box 2, Print WC28)
    Excavation for hospital and medical school buildings?
  - West Campus Progress Picture #29, 1927 September 8 (Box 2, Print WC29)
    Site of Academic Quadrangle showing railroad track. Site of Medical School is at center of photograph.
  - West Campus Progress Picture #30, 1927 September 8 (Box 2, Print WC30)
    Excavation, location undetermined.
  - West Campus Progress Picture #31, 1927 September 8 (Box 2, Print WC31)
  - West Campus Progress Picture #32, 1927 September 8 (Box 2, Print WC32)
    View east along future causeway, with portions of future Circuit Drive roughed in.
  - West Campus Progress Picture #35, 1927 November 14 (Box 2, Print WC35)
    View towards Main Quadrangle from site of Craven Quadrangle [Craven Residence Hall] showing excavation and forms for dormitory?
  - West Campus Progress Picture #36, 1927 November 14 (Box 2, Print WC36)
    Excavation for Craven Quadrangle [Craven Residence Hall], looking south?
  - West Campus Progress Picture #37, 1927 November 29 (Box 2, Print WC37)
    Site of Residential Quadrangle looking northwest?
  - West Campus Progress Picture #38, 1927 November 29 (Box 2, Print WC38)
    Site of Residential Quadrangles looking southwest?
  - West Campus Progress Picture #39, 1927 November 29 (Box 2, Print WC39)
  - West Campus Progress Picture #40, 1927 November 29 (Box 2, Print WC40)
  - West Campus Progress Picture #41, 1928 January 3 (Box 2, Print WC41)
    From back of photo: "Picture taken from near Union Building, looking along front of Dormitories. This shows the concrete foundation fninished up to grade of Main Quadrangle."
  - West Campus Progress Picture #42, 1928 January 3 (Box 2, Print WC42)
    From back of photo: "Picture taken from near Service entrance, looking towards main entrance of Hospital, which entrance is located where mixer now stands. This shows concrete wall around sub-basement."
  - West Campus Progress Picture #43, 1928 January 3 (Box 2, Print WC43)
    From back of photo: "Picture taken from near entrance of Group 'C' Dormitory [Kilgo Quadrangle] looking towards Union Building. This shows the front wall of Group 'C' dormitory built up to Quadrangle grade, also forms built for concrete foundation of Union Building. A large pile of stone is located between Union building and Library."
  - West Campus Progress Picture #44, 1928 January 3 (Box 2, Print WC44)
    From back of photo: "Taken from Quadrangle in front of Chapel, looking across Union Building, with Group 'C' Dormitory [Kilgo Quadrangle] in the background. This shows mixing plant and forms for Union Building."
  - West Campus Progress Picture #45, 1928 January 3 (Box 2, Print WC45)
    From back of photo: "Taken from near the center of Medical School, looking across the hospital. This shows part of the service tunnel under basement floor. Mixer is located at the main entrance to hospital."
  - West Campus Progress Picture #46, 1928 January 3 (Box 2, Print WC46)
    From back of photo: "Taken from service court at far end of Group 'C' dormitories [Kilgo Quadrangle]. This looking across Group 'C' Dormitories and Union Building, and shows forms on right of picture ready for pouring first floor of Group 'C' Dormitories. The location of the Hospital and Medical School is shown in the upper center of the picture."
  - West Campus Progress Picture #47, 1928 February 2 (Box 2, Print WC47)
    From back of photo: "Taken from end of Group 'C' Dormitories [Kilgo Quadrangle] looking across Union Building toward location for School of Religion."
  - West Campus Progress Picture #48, 1928 February 2 (Box 2, Print WC48)
    From back of photo: "Showing close-up detail of the Hospital near the Service Entrance. This shows sub-basement of Hospital."
  - West Campus Progress Picture #49, 1928 February 2 (Box 2, Print WC49)
    From back of photo: "Union Buliding in foreground with Group 'C' Dormitories [Kilgo Quadrangle] in the background."
  - West Campus Progress Picture #50, 1928 February 2 (Box 2, Print WC50)
    From back of photo: "Taken near Union Building looking across Group 'C' Dormitories [Kilgo Quadrangle]."
  - West Campus Progress Picture #51, 1928 February 2 (Box 2, Print WC51)
    From back of photo: "Taken from entrance to Medical School looking across Hospital."
  - West Campus Progress Picture #52, 1928 February 2 (Box 2, Print WC52)
    From back of photo: "Taken from extreme rear end looking across Group 'C' Dormitories [Kilgo Quadrangle] and Union Building, with Hospital and Medical School in background."
  - West Campus Progress Picture #53, 1928 March 5 (Box 2, Print WC53)
    From back of photo: "View showing stonework laid on rear of Group 'C' Dormitories [Kilgo Quadrangle]. This shows stonework at the highest approximate level with First Floor."
  - West Campus Progress Picture #54, 1928 March 5 (Box 2, Print WC54)
    From back of photo: "View taken from Medical College looking across Hospital showing all foundations placed ready for steel work, and practically all backfilling completed around concrete. Also showing railroad track laid through the center of Hospital."
  - West Campus Progress Picture #55, 1928 March 5 (Box 2, Print WC55)
    From back of photo: "View showing part of foundation for Hospital near Service Entrance. Extreme lower left shows sub-basement."
  - West Campus Progress Picture #56, 1928 March 5 (Box 2, Print WC56)
    From back of photo: "View taken from end of group 'C' Dormitories [Kilgo Quadrangle], looking across Union Building. This shows outside walls of Union Building and foundation of basement floor level."
  - West Campus Progress Picture #57, 1928 March 5 (Box 2, Print WC57)
    From back of photo: "View taken from service court back of Group 'C' Dormitories [Kilgo Quadrangle] showing First Floor of Group 'C' Dormitories, with steel columns erected along corridors."
  - West Campus Progress Picture #58, 1928 March 5 (Box 2, Print WC58)
    From back of photo: "View taken from rear of Union Building looking across same toward Group 'C' Dormitories [Kilgo Quadrangle]. This shows forms being constructed for the Basement floor. The concrete shown in the center of the picture is up to the elevation of the Basement floor."
  - West Campus Progress Picture #59, 1928 April 3 (Box 2, Print WC59)
    From back of photo: "View looking across the foundation for Hospital and Medical School. Shows derrick being set up for erecting steel structure."
  - West Campus Progress Picture #60, 1928 April 3 (Box 2, Print WC60)
    From back of photo: "Taken from Court in front of Chapel looking across Union Building foundation. This shows Union Building concrete completed to Basement Floor. In the background is shown Group 'C' Dormitory [Kilgo Quadrangle] with window frames set to First Floor."
  - West Campus Progress Picture #61, 1928 April 5 (Box 2, Print WC61)
    From back of photo: "View taken from approximate location of Group 'C' Dormitory [Kilgo Quadrangle], looking toward the rear of Group 'C' Dormitory, showing structural steel and stone work."
  - West Campus Progress Picture #62, 1928 April 5 (Box 2, Print WC62)
    From back of photo: "View taken from Main Quadrangle at entrance of Medical School looking across Medical School and Hospital foundation."
  - West Campus Progress Picture #63, 1928 April 5 (Box 2, Print WC63)
    From back of photo: "View taken from Main Quadrangle between Union Building and Group 'C' Dormitory [Kilgo Quadrangle], looking across Union Building, showing concrete basement floor complete, and on right, forms being erected for First Floor of the Union Building. In center of picture is shown excavation for Class Room and Auditorium. In upper center is shown location for Chapel."
  - West Campus Progress Picture #64, 1928 April 5 (Box 2, Print WC64)
    From back of photo: "Taken from end of building showing a close-up detail of Group 'C' Dormitory [Kilgo Quadrangle] where same connects to Union Building."
  - West Campus Progress Picture #65, 1928 May 1 (Box 2, Print WC65)
    From back of photo: "View taken from the rear Service Court of Group 'C' Dormitories showing stone work and steel erected."
  - West Campus Progress Picture #66, 1928 May 1 (Box 2, Print WC66)
    From back of photo: "View taken from end of Medical College looking across Hospital showing steel erected up to second floor level on the Hospital end of the building."
  - West Campus Progress Picture #67, 1928 May 1 (Box 2, Print WC67)
    From back of photo: "View showing the front of Group 'C' Dormitories [Kilgo Quadrangle] adjoining the Union Building."
  - West Campus Progress Picture #68, 1928 May 1 (Box 2, Print WC68)
    From back of photo: "View looking across basement floor of Union Building showing Group 'C' Dormitories [Kilgo Quadrangle] in the background."
  - West Campus Progress Picture #69, 1928 May 1 (Box 2, Print WC69)
    From back of photo: "View of Hospital taken from Service Court showing steel erected from sub-basement floor to second floor."
  - West Campus Progress Picture #70, 1928 May 1 (Box 2, Print WC70)
    From back of photo: "View taken from end of Group 'C' Dormitories [Kilgo Quadrangle] looking across Union Building, showing forms being erected above basement floor."
  - West Campus Progress Picture #71, 1928 May 30 (Box 2, Print WC71)
    From back of photo: "View looking at the rear of Group 'C' Dormitories [Kilgo Quadrangle] showing stone work completed to third floor level."
  - West Campus Progress Picture #72, 1928 May 31 (Box 2, Print WC72)
    From back of photo: "View showing the front of Group 'C' Dormitories [Kilgo Quadrangle] near location of Group 'B' Dormitories [Crowell Quadrangle]. This shows stonework on the front of the Building built up to the third floor level."
  - West Campus Progress Picture #73, 1928 May 30 (Box 2, Print WC73)
    From back of photo: "View showing the Entrance Court to Hospital. Showing structural steel erected on this part of the building to fourth floor." [Dated 1928-05-31 on back of photo]
  - West Campus Progress Picture #74, 1928 May 30 (Box 2, Print WC74)
    From back of photo: "View taken from end of Medical School looking across Medical School and Hospital, showing steel partly erected to fourth floor on Hospital end of Building." [Dated 1928-05-31 on back of photo]
  - West Campus Progress Picture #75, 1928 May 30 (Box 2, Print WC75)
    From back of photo: "View of Heating Plant showing foundations for building coal trestle and stack." [Dated 1928-05-31 on back of photo]
  - West Campus Progress Picture #76, 1928 May 30 (Box 2, Print WC76)
    From back of photo: "View taken from front of Library looking across same, with foundation for School of Religion at right of picture." [Dated 1928-05-31 on back of photo]
  - West Campus Progress Picture #77, 1928 May 30 (Box 2, Print WC77)